Ashburn, VA 20148 (571) 357-0234

Ericg8251@gmail.com <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-f-garcia-a8130415">http://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-f-garcia-a8130415</a>

GitHub.io: https://ericgarcia38.github.io/github.io/

Nationality: French. Permanent US Resident / Green Card holder. Public Trust Clearance.

# Senior Software Engineer and Project Manager. Specialized in the Lending/Loan/Credit/Mortgages/Leasing area.

Technology-focused professional with broad based experience delivering on-time solutions and meaningful process improvements well prepared to significantly impact operations and profitability in a software engineering role.

Team-oriented leader with project management expertise leading strategic technology projects, including applications, software and hardware solutions. Develops and leverages internal and external relationships to maximize the achievement of business goals; ensures business and technology solutions are aligned, secure, and compliant with corporate strategies. Uses Agile and SCRUM methodologies to manage risk, control, and deliver quality, accurate products for the customer. Focuses on processes; review established processes, identify underperforming components, develop modifications and implement them across the organization. Values data; consistently measuring progress and performance through models, metrics, and research to inform project decisions.

#### **Core Competencies:**

Project Management	Data Analysis	Relationship Management	Industry Expertise
<ul><li>SCRUM/Agile</li><li>Prioritization</li></ul>	<ul><li>Budgeting</li><li>Forecasting</li></ul>	<ul><li>Technical Support</li><li>Vendor</li></ul>	<ul><li>Banking</li><li>Consumer</li></ul>
		Management	<ul><li>Finance</li><li>Mortgage</li></ul>
<ul> <li>Deliverable Management</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Process Improvement</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Negotiations</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Leasing</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Software Development Life Cycle</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Technology Implementation</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Problem Solving</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Fleet</li> <li>Management</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Data Migration</li> </ul>			

#### **Technical Proficiencies**

OS	IBM P6-7, AS-400, LINUX, WINDOWS SERVER
----	---

ETL Informatica, Talent

Database Oracle, DB2, Mysql

Software CASSIOPAE, EVOLAN, Software Research, MIMIX

Languages PL/SQL, RPG ILE , C,C#,VB.net, C++, JAVA , DELPHI 1- 10.2 , Javascript,Python

(2020)

Frameworks Sencha Ext Js, Jquery , Nodejs, Jasper, LANSA, Salesforce (sandbox 2017)

## **Professional Experience**

Strongbridge LLC. Sterling, VA 2020-Present

#### Senior Engineer Developer - Java and Delphi for DOL WHD DC

I develop and maintain projects written in JAVA, HIBERNATE and Delphi for the U.S. Department of Labor . The working environment revolves around JIRA for monitoring tickets and requirements, DB2 for the database and IBM Rational and GITLAB for the versioning and revision control . Delphi 7 and Delphi 10.2 Tokyo, for content developed in Delphi. I modify and transfer the existing client / server applications to the latest version of Embarcadero.

I modify and create Java applications with hibernate in the payroll domain.

I modify or create PL/SQL procedures to facilitate the link between the programs and the DB2 Database.

Cassiopae US. Burlington, MA 2013 – 2020

Senior Engineer - Delivery Manager.

Loan / Leasing (Cassiopae) Oracle , PL/SQL C++, DELPHI- XE 10.3 , Jasper Report , JAVA , SOAP UI

Cassiopae is a Financial software for loans, leasing and mortgages done in Java ADF connected to Oracle,

The core program could be installed as a Saas service on **AWS** or as a stand alone program on client Infra.

I collaborate with clients to clearly define the project scope, objectives, and success metrics.

I implement the settings based on the Business requirements with Sql and **PL/SQL**. I follow up , debug , monitor , and install the application on Tomcat or Weblogic. I debug and analyze the weblogic logs.

I debug ,modify and create **WSDL** services. (Eclipse and SoapUI). I update or create the **JAVA** programs in **ADF** and **Spring Core**. (**REST services**).

I managed and create an **ODS** behind Cassiopae Database for operational reporting and as a source of data for the EDW. This ODS is managed with the **ETL Talent**. All the events are triggered in the DB Cassiopae and send messages to a **JMS** queue. The service client in listening receives these messages and runs the **ETL Talent** java programs to feed out **ODS** in real time.

Regarding the batch programs and financial core, they are written in C++.

These programs are connected to Oracle with **instantclient v12**, and call **PLSQL** stored procedures or SQL statements. I debug and maintain the batch programs in **C++** such as:

- batch invoicing for the generation of the receivables.
- batch accounting for the generation of the accounting events.
- Batch for variables rates. (re-calculation of amortization schedule).

The versioning is done in **SVN** and tracked in **JIRA**.

I build the **JASPER** reports in Java and **PLSQL**.

I manage as PM and create the programs for the data migration from the legacy to Oracle.

2013-Austin TX → DELL FS: migration INFOLEASE to Cassiopae Front office.

2015-Sterling VA → CFC : migration SYBASE legacy to Cassiopae ORACLE Back/Front office.

2016-Washington DC  $\rightarrow$  IDB: migration legacy to Cassiopae Back/Front office.

2018-Malvern PA  $\rightarrow$  SIEMENS : migration INFOLEASE to Cassiopae Back/Front office.

I manage the Oracle **DB on AWS**, and Backup/Restore snapshots.

I create the shell Unix to create batches to incorporate in the **JENKINS** processes.

Furthermore, I created the business requirements, mockups, and worked on the project of management of delivery SQL scripts through Oracle which have to be linked to a Bank software. The general requirement was to share a place where all the consultants have to enter their own scripts, and then to manage the Master script in a **DEVOPS** environment. (connected to git, **jenkins** and **Jira**).

The project was developed with Delphi XE<sub>5</sub> and Builder C++ as a Web application , with **AJAX** requests technologies and **RESTFUL** services , to publish the main CRUD functions.

Then a Front End built with the framework **SENCHA Ext/Js** and **JQUERY** can consume **these RESTFUL** services.

Societe Generale Consumer Finance. Paris, France, 2006 – 2012

Software engineer and Country Manager for Consumer Loan on ISERIES (SOPRA EVOLAN), RPG ILE, COBOL , Db2, Db2/400, Java

Selected Projects & Achievements:

- I Lead and develop a project to downsize hardware and software utilization for a mid-sized organization; after implementation the customer costs fell almost \$4 million annually. For the security connections I Developed an emulation 5250 for Iseries/As400 with securities keywords, in order to cover the security and trace of connections to the mainframe.
- The software was developed in DELPHI 2007 for the 5250 Emulation and DELPHI XE2 and Builder C++
  for Database security management as an intranet WEB application, all connected to a DB2/400 server
  with server programs written in RPGLE and CLLE.
- I Deploy, implement and develop a Lending Software for the Back and Front office in the Subsidiaries Bank in east countries. As country manager I manage and follow up the budget for the following countries: Tcheck Republic, Greece, Kazakhstan and Croatia.
- I manage the front-office Java program in **JSP with HIBERNATE**, and the deployment on Websphere IBM.
- I modify, adapt and create programs in COBOL, RPGLE, CLLE on ISERIES P7.

Crédit Immobilier EST . Metz, Strasbourg, France , 2004 – 2006

#### Consultant - IBM. Mortgage Migration from UNIX Progress to ISERIES Db2/400,

Consultant and project manager, for a data migration project from Unix Progress tools (VINCI software to an **AS400 database** Finance Software)

- I create the Interfaces between the business teams in order to migrate the Legacy to the new system in **RPGLE, CLP**
- I Manage the full project and specifically the accounting and financial domains.
- I create programs to upload the data into DB2. /400 13500 mortgages (Rpg ILE, CLLE, DELPHI 2007).
- I create a web application to collect the new / old settings and the user story .

#### technologies used:

- Back and front server in Rad PHP
- Data Model created on **Mysql Db**
- Interfaces to Iserie **DB2**, **C++**.

President GDB SYSTEMS GRENOBLE, France, 2002 – 2004

#### PM and SENIOR ISERIES Engineer .C++/ C# .Net developer

Acting as President of the company GDB-SYSTEMS, I was commissioned as Project Manager for BNP Bank, to work on the new arrangements for EBICS banking transfers in Europe. This solution had to run on a Windows station connected to an IBM AS400 (DB2). The solution has been developed around DELPHI7, C# .Net for the front in ASP and RPG-ILE on ISERIES for the back.

Creation of the software Flash400; FTP tool on AS400 developed in Delphi and C++.

Creation of the software Install'400: Tool used to install softwares on the **AS400** middleware. Developed in **Delphi and C++**.

I also develop software in the Mail industrie, interfaced to the machines Pitney Bowes. The software is broken down in 2 parts.

- Linux Camera to capture the images (QR2 code) and send information to the server. Use of C and C++.
- Server to retrieve the entries and guide the sorting machine PB. Technologies used:
- .NET C#, VB.net, ASP.NET for the core of the system.

EASII, Rhône Alpes, France, 1992 – 2002.

#### CTO at Credit Immobilier de Grenoble

- Creation of a tool box VBX/ACTIVEX for companies as ASNA (TX San Antonio) and LANSA (VBX Toolkit) ASPECT COMPUTING (Australia, Sydney) to connect in native mode (no SQL) to DB2 400.
- Management of 10 developers in Delphi and C++.
- Creation of a Mortgage software for the Credit Immobilier Grenoble with the below capacities.
  - o Financial core. C/C++/CLP/RPG
  - o back Office LANSA
  - o front Office LANSA/SERVER and ACTIVEX for LANSA
  - o Accounting LANSA
  - o reporting RPGLE
  - o Securitization and due diligence interface. Pascal/C++, VB (VBX Toolkit)
- Data Migration:
  - o 1995 Migration of 3 Credit Immobilier (Isere 38) in a common subsidiary company:
    - 90.000 Mortgages.
  - o 1999 Migration of 4 Credit Immobilier (PARIS 75):
    - 13.000 Mortgages.
- Outsourcing offer for the Credit Immobilier Rhone Alpes with the following tasks .
  - o Supervision AS400 on a daily basis.
  - o Installation Ptf'fs.
  - o Configuration network, in Sna and Tcp/ip.
  - o Installation releases.
  - o Backup strategy, journalisation.
  - o management raid 5.
  - o monitoring messages.
  - o Development of tools in **Clp Clle RPG, COBOL** for the maintenance of the mortgage software MCO..

## **Education**

#### Master of Science, Enterprise Data Processing (1987)

CNAM of GRENOBLE, Grenoble, France

#### Certifications

IBM P6-7, AS-400 : Fontenay sous bois IBM France 1990 Delphi, C++ Developer Grenoble 38000 France 1995

MiMix: Garches 92000 France 2003 Oracle PL/SQL. 75000 France 2008 Python: Udemy 2020 (in progress)

#### Nationality

French. Permanent US Resident / Green Card holder.